Guide to the Betty Berzon papers,1972-1979.
Berzon, Betty papers, 1972-1979
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Betty Berzon papers, 1972-1979.
7312
Betty Berzon
1 cubic foot.
Audiotapes, printed materials, manuscripts, ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Tape recordings of a UCLA Extension Program, "The Homosexual in America," June 21, 1972; printed materials; and memorabilia, including buttons, reflecting the women's liberation movements in the 1970s, chiefly in Los Angeles and Southern California. Includes documentation of the Briggs Initiative to prohibit lesbian and gay teachers from being employed by public schools.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Author and gay/lesbian leader in Los Angeles.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Tape recordings of a UCLA Extension Program, "The Homosexual in America," June 21, 1972; printed materials; and memorabilia, including buttons, reflecting the women's liberation movements in the 1970s, chiefly in Los Angeles and Southern California. Includes documentation of the Briggs Initiative to prohibit lesbian and gay teachers from being employed by public schools.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Berzon, Betty.
Subjects:
Homosexuality.; Lesbians.; Women's liberation.--California.; Briggs Initiative.; Lesbian and gay teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Ephemera
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- UCLA Extension Program: The Homosexual in America, copy, June 1972; 1mm, 7" reel (Box 1)
- UCLA Extension Program: The Homosexual in America, 2 tapes, June 1971; 1mm, 7" reel (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous leaflets, letters, and flyers (Box 1)
- Copy of Supreme Court of the State of California California Federation of Teachers...v. March Fong EU, Secretary of State, Respondent, John V. Briggs, Real Party in Interest (S.F. No. 23840), 1978 (Box 1)
- FPS: A Magazine of Young People's Liberation, 1976 (Box 1)
- Quotations from Chief Ed (Or: Six Years With Foot-in-mouth Disease), 1976 (Box 1)
- December 1980 Community Center (Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center Hollywood, CA) (Box 1)
- A Straight Couple Looks In-- by Bill and Mary Davis, 1978 (Box 1)
- Multi-Media Resource Center Book List 1001 Book Titles, 1970s (Box 1)
- Stonewall Democratic Club "A Tribute to Morris Knight" Program, November 1979 (Box 1)
- Stonewall Democratic Club "A Tribute to Ivy Bottini" Program, January 1981 (Box 1)
- "The Ballad of Thomas and Mary (Songs of Gay Liberation)" by Raymond S. 'Arby' Baxter, unknown (Box 1)
- SCW/WRF NEWS (Southern California Women for the Whitman-Radclyffe Foundation) Vol. 1, unknown (Box 1)
- The Gay Academic Union Fifth National Conference Hosted by the USC Gay Student Union University of Southern California November 24-26, 1978, November 1978 (Box 1)
- "On My Way to Nowhere: alienated, isolated, drunk" An Analysis of Gay Alcohol Abuse and An Evaluation of Alcoholism Rehabilitation Services for the Los Angeles Gay Community", July 1975 (Box 1)
- Gay Academic Union Newsletter Volume Two, Number 1, Spring 1979 (Box 1)
- Sunset Junction Street Fair Progam 1981 (Box 1)
- First Annual Report of Gay Rights Advocates (the operating arm of the Legal Foundation for Personal Liberties), February 1979 (Box 1)
- Report from the Board of Directors Gay Community Services Center, Los Angeles, May 20, 1975, May 1975 (Box 1)
- The Business and Professional Association of Los Angeles Pamphlet, 1980 (Box 1)
- Assorted Pins and Buttons, Various Gay Pride Events, 1970s (Box 1)
- Index to Sexual Reporter Volume Three-1977, 1979 (Box 1)
- Volume Two, Numbers 3, 4, 5, 6; Volume Three, Numbers 1, 2, 3, 4, 5; Volume Four, Number 4, 1976-1978 (Box 1)